Mushfiqur Rahman

| mushfiq.rumc@gmail.com | 709-986-8792 | Glace Bay. NS |

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/sunmushfiq | GitHub: https://github.com/fmmr32

RELEVANT SKILLS AND QUALIFICATIONS

Technical Skills

Structured & OOP Languages C++, Java, Python, MATLAB

Scripting Language PHP, JavaScript, TypeScript, Perl, Python
 Database MongoDB, MySQL, NoSQL, Postgres SQL

Libraries and Frameworks
 NodeJS, VUE JS, Express JS, SFML, Yii2, Underscore JS, Laravel

o Source and version Control GitHub, Docker, Git, SourceTree

Architectures
 Model-View-Controller (MVC), Entity-Component-System (ECS)

Web Services and other
 AWS, SOAP, REST, SharePoint, Microsoft Office Tools
 DNS, Firewall, HTTP/HTTPS, FTP, SFTP, VPN, IPSEC

- Analytical Skills and Knowledge Completed tasks with highly detailed oriented and strong analytical skills
 using tailored strategical, impeccable judgement & knowledge for clients' core requirements, investigating
 complex concerns, identifying risk & opportunities, and implementing right strategic recommendation for
 clients.
- Client Service Skills Excellent relationship management and communications skills with an ability to build strong relationships at all levels.
- **Communication Skills** Exercised excellent verbal and written communication skills through documentation and briefing teams on client activities through presentation at staff meetings.
- Enthusiastic Team Player Demonstrated strong leadership roles through effective collaboration with team members and by always articulating new ideas and implementing strategies for the ongoing process improvement & development of team to better serve clients, ensuring client's need at the top.

EXPERIENCE OVERVIEW

Full-Stack Developer experienced in working in an agile environment.

Project Management experience practicing best methodologies using JIRA and Trello

Developed test Driven back-end and front-end reusable code following best practices.

 ${\bf Experienced\,in\,AWS\,(EC2,S3\,database,VPC,VPN,Connect,Custom\,Integrations)}.$

Built Custom Game Engines and level editor for 2D web based multi category games.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer - Binogi Studios Ltd 2023-2024

https://www.binogi.ca/

Duties/Responsibilities

- Plan, design and Budget multiple backend projects maintaining constant communication with management and frontend team to deliver cost friendly microservices adhering to EU privacy laws.
- Enhance, facilitate, and fix project related issues reported by clients, users, and management.
- Investigate and execute security, bug fixes.

Experience Highlight

- Development of multiple microservices using PHP, Laravel, Postgres SQL, with tests and swagger documentation.
- Planned security enhancement referencing OWASP top 10.
- Normalize databases with regards to the New EU GDPR standards
- Overall tech stack operations budgeting
- Enhance engagement with AWS services (Eventbridge, SQS, ElastiCache etc)

Success Snapshot

Developed several PHP-based tools to streamline Mixpanel product analysis by accessing client databases.

Mushfiqur Rahman

| mushfiq.rumc@gmail.com | 709-986-8792 | Glace Bay. NS |

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/sunmushfiq | GitHub: https://github.com/fmmr32

- Enhanced scheduling tools for releasing educational content and quizzes using AWS SQS.
- Implemented the design and construction of multiple databases in compliance with EU privacy standards, utilizing PostgreSQL and PHP.
- Coordinated the design, planning, budgeting, and development of various education-focused projects across Canada, the US, Sweden, Germany, and India.

Software Developer-Tax Dollar Inc

2021-2023

https://taxdollar.ca/

Duties/Responsibilities

- Building a new server from scratch using Raspberry Pi, Nginx, Node JS & Express JS.
- Developing new frontend using Vue Js and Vuetify Js to upgrade from client's old technology-based frontend.
- Customized development of agile environment to ensure client's heavy involvement in the design and requirement process.

Success Snapshot

- Backend Implementation of strategies to normalize old database migration at a largescale for upgrade, using Nginx as server, ensuring client's current standards are met efficiently.
- Development of better techniques to splice data into paginations and lazy loading to handle large databases, to ensure Rest Api calls made to updated database are sufficient to confront significant delay on data transfer to the frontend,
- Development of email servers using SMTP from scratch while uploading multiple files using Busboy Js which that pass the JWT and Nginx security protocols.
- Application of Axios to make REST API calls.
- Implementation of JSON Web Token to ensure proper security.
- Developed a new calendar appointment system, ensure in-depth overlay look of varied views, ensuring effective management of tasks and goals.

Experience Highlights BACK END:

- Migration from cloud hosted server and storage to On-site Server build based on RaspberryPi with local storage management using Nginx, Express Js, Node Js, and axios tocommunicate with mongoDB database – per business requirements.
- Two-way communication protocols developed using customSMPT email server
- integrated visa, Mastercard and interac payment systems.
- Secured custom file transfer protocols using Busboy Js, Multer Js for different tiers of users and documents.
- Secured communication implementation for front andbackend using JWT as middleware.

Software Developer-Business Drives Inc 2020-2020

https://www.businessdrives.com/

- Developed software solutions unique to clients' needs, by researching information needs, conferring with users, and studying systems flow, data usage, and work processes, investigating problem areas, and integrating into client system
 - Automated a previously tedious process of appointment reminder calls that was previously managed by 18 employees by using AWS
 Connect to enhance accessibility for clients with special needs.

Experience Highlight

FRONTEND:

- Development of a No Codeplatform unique to client requirements using Vue Js and Yii frameworks.
- Designed, developed, and integrated automated call centersolution to client website using Amazon Connect API

BACKEND: Designed and developed conformance tests using SOAPAPI and REST API

Mushfiqur Rahman

| mushfiq.rumc@gmail.com | 709-986-8792 | Glace Bay. NS |

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/sunmushfiq | GitHub: https://github.com/fmmr32

- Identified areas for modification in existing programs and subsequently developing these modifications
 - Integrated eFax solution to client website for better reachability with sites lacking fax machines.
- Communicated subsequent modification to clients effectively.
 - Post-implementation conducted eFax usage guidance to company's ~100 frontline nurses (end-users)
 - Monitored and provided ongoing support to eFax usage by end users ensuring highest efficiency.
- Prepared technical reports & client summaries and conducted presentation of findings, facts, and highlights to team and clients.
- Designed and implemented conformance tests required by Health Ministry of Canada for database access and integrated other medical services to client systems.
 - Access to Patient history database, data transfer and storage requirements of Zeiss machine technologies to local and cloud data storage.

- Backend practices to supportfrontend requirements by clients using Node Js, PHP, JavaScript, pgAdmin (NoSQL)
- Created and managed servers and storages using AWS EC2 instances and AWS S3 storages
- Integrated eFaxing solutions to client website using eFax

PROJECTS

Binogi Studios - https://www.binogi.com/

2023-2024

Summary: Binogi is a multilingual, digital learning platform operating in multiple countries that offers animated lessons and interactive quizzes in immigrant student's mother tongue for better learning adaptivity in a foreign country.

Tech Stack: React, PHP, Laravel, SSOs, AWS S3, EC2, VPC, ElastiCache, Elasticsearch, SNS, EventBridge, SQS, multiple payment services integration, MixPanel.

Tax Dollar Inc - https://www.taxdollar.ca

2021

Summary: A complete website and solutions for Tax Dollar Inc for their internal use and client interface **Technology Used**: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.JS, Node Express, Nginx, Vue, Vuetify, Busboy, SMTP, Visa Checkout integration.

Clarity-https://www.clarityeye.ca

2020

Summary: Complete software, website, and call center solution for Clarity Eye Institute **Technology Used:** MVC, PHP, Yii2, JavaScript, Vue JS, underscore JS, Node JS, AWS (EC2, S3, Connect, VPC, VPN), NoSQL database, SOAPand REST APIs, SFTP, IPSEC

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science, Minor - Mathematics

Graduation 2019

Memorial University of Newfoundland, St John's, NL, CA

AWARDS/ACCOMPLISHMENT

- Silver Award for excellence in volunteering, Memorial University of Newfoundland
- Bronze Award for excellence in volunteering, Memorial University of Newfoundland